veloviewer.com 2019-06-16

# Privacy Policy | VeloViewer

Privacy matters but it can be confusing. This page explains our approach to privacy on the VeloViewer websites and how it affects you.

## Short version

  * We collect anonymous statistics about your visit, like which of our pages you viewed.
  * Some 3rd parties like Strava, Facebook and Twitter may know you visited this website, if you use their services. We can’t control them but we don’t believe this knowledge poses any threat to you.
  * If you connect your Strava account with us we take great care to keep your information safe and we’ll never share it with others without your express permission.
  * None of your data stored by us is publicly available unless you opt-in to make it public in the Options section of your [Update page](https://veloviewer.com/update) and then only the data publicly available in Strava is available via VeloViewer to users other than yourself.
  * We never share your data with 3rd parties.

These are just the key points. If you need detail, keep reading.

## Measuring our visitors

We measure visitors to our website using Google Analytics. This records what pages you view within our site, how you arrived at our site and some basic information about your computer. All of that information is anonymous (athlete/activity/route ids are stripped from the URL before being sent to Google Analytics and your IP address is anonymised) – so we don’t know who you are; just that  _somebody  _visited our site.

The information we collect from analytics helps us understand what parts of our sites are doing well, how people arrive at our site and so on. Like most websites, we use this information to make our website better.

You can learn more about [Google Analytics](https://www.google.com/analytics/learn/privacy.html "Google Analytics' privacy policy") or [opt out if you wish](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout "How to opt out of Google Analytics").

## Facebook, Twitter and other social networks

These services provide social buttons and similar features which we use on our website – such as the “Like” and “Tweet” buttons.

To do so we embed code that they provide and we do not control ourselves. To function their buttons generally know if you’re logged in; for example Facebook use this to say “x of your friends like this”. We do not have any access to that information, nor can we control how those networks use it.

Social networks therefore  _could  _know that you’re viewing this website, if you use their services (that isn’t to say they do, but their policies may change). As our website is remarkably inoffensive we imagine this is not a concern for most users.

## Storing of personal information

When you connect your Strava account – free or PRO – we will record specific personal information about you, such as your name and email address provided by the Strava API.

Your Strava data will be cached securely on our servers in order to provide a responsive user experience when using the site.

All of your data stored in VeloViewer gathered via the Strava API can be deleted using the button in the Options section of your [Update page](https://veloviewer.com/update).

We also log payment history for accounting and tax purposes which includes your name, address, the email address associated with your PayPal account and a reference to your unique Strava number to link the payment to your account. These can not be deleted.

## Cookies

Three types of cookies are used on VeloViewer:

  1. VeloViewer Session cookies – these persist for the length of your session with the server and store details that are required to authenticate your session against your Strava login.
  2. VeloViewer Permanent cookies – these are stored indefinitely in your browser and are used to improve your user experience by persisting display settings e.g. default map style to be used.  VeloViewer does not use cookies to track you and does not include any information in the cookies that can be used to identify you.
  3. 3rd Party Cookies – where external controls are embedded in VeloViewer, these sites will use there own cookies. Currently Strava, Facebook and Twitter.

## Emails

We may send you email notifications regarding your service (such as a renewal reminder) but we won’t use your email for any other purpose.

We will  _never  _provide your personal information or email address to any third parties.

## Online payment

We use PayPal to take payment for access to our service online. PayPal will have access to your personal and payment information. VeloViewer themselves do not ever have any access to your credit card or bank details nor do they have the ability to take a payment that you haven’t already set up yourself.

We share information with these companies only to the extent necessary for the purposes of processing payments you make via our website in order to link the payment to your account in VeloViewer.

## Security

VeloViewer take many precautions to prevent the loss, misuse or alteration of your personal information. These precautions include:

  * Use of SSL encryption
  * Hardware stored in secured datacentres behind firewalls
  * All access to information restricted by password and/or secure key
  * Restrictions to what information can be accessed via any location

Whilst we take great care to ensure any confidential information remains protected we cannot guarantee the security of data sent over the Internet.

Of course you are responsible for keeping your password and user details confidential. Nobody at VeloViewer will ever ask you for your Strava password, so please don’t trust anybody asking you for it. VeloViewer never has access to your Strava password i.e. when you connect your Strava account.

## Updates to this policy

We may update this privacy policy from time-to-time, particularly as technology changes. You can always check this page for the latest version.

## Any questions?

If you have any questions about this privacy policy or your personal data, please write to us by email to [veloviewer@gmail.com](mailto:veloviewer@gmail.com)
